Guide to the Alison Jolly papers, circa 1919-2014
Jolly, Alison papers
- Series III. Notes and Papers
  - General Documents
    - Flat Feet, Clever Hands Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2004; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Lowly Origin, Jonathan Kingdon, London Review of Books 7 October, 2004, 28
    - Love, Actually Author: AJ Lewes, 2004; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Why we love, Helen Fisher, Nature 427:396-397
    - The Wide Spectrum of Sex and Gender Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 2004; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Evolutions Rainbow, Joan Roughgarden, Science 304: 965-966
    - The Last Great Apes? Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2005; article (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Science: 2 september, Vol. 309
    - Life and Death in Sumatra Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2005; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Among Orangutans: Red Apes and the Rise of Human Culture, Carel van Schaik, Nature 433:462
    - A Global Vision Author: AJ Lewes, 2006; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      The Ecological Theatre and the Evolutionary Play, G.E. Hutchinson, Nature 443:148
    - The Social Origin of Mind Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2007; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Baboon Metaphysics: The Evolution of a Social Mind, D.L. Cheney, Robert M. Seyfarth, Science 317:1326-1327
    - Macachavellian Intelligence Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2007; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Dario Maestripieri, Times Higher Ed. Supplement Oct 5, 2007
    - Primate Passions Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2007; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Jane Goodall: The Woman who redefined man, Dale Peterson, Amer. Scientist 95:79-81
    - The Narrator's Stance: Storytelling and Science at Berenty Reserve Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 2011; Typed article (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Centralizing Fieldwork: Critical Perspectives from Primatology, Biological and Social Anthropology, J MacClancy and A. Fuentes
    - Berenty tourism typed letter and calendar (2006) Author: RJ, Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, typed letter (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Eulemur fulvus census Author: Susan Pinkus Location: Berenty, 1993; papers, photos and notes (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Eulemur fulvus census for 1993 - sept-nov
    - Influences des conditions de l'habitat sur les structures de la papulation de propithecus verreauxi verreauxi Author: Soava Victor Rakotoarisoa Location: Berenty, paper, notes and tables (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Wrist flexion as a distinction between lemuroid and lorisoid prehensive grasps Author: AJ, Zackary Taylor Berenty, 1999; paper, notes and discs (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - prints, photos and stamps Location: Haiti, 1970s-80s; photos, stamps (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Solenodon
    - Lemur behaviour Author: AMKB, Hugh Rowell, RJ Location: Berenty, 1965; drawings and photos (Box 24, Folder 1)
      AMKB, RBJ, Hugh Rowell, L. Collaris
    - Alison Jolly Thesis Author: AJ, AMKB Yale, 1963; original plates and negs (Box 3, Folder 12)
      lemur Yale
    - Alison Jolly Thesis Author: AJ, AMKB Yale, 1963; original plates and negs (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Flight from Morondava Author: Alison Jolly Kirindy, Analabe, Tsingy, Bongolava, 1975; photos, stamps (Box 3, Folder 9)
      J.J. Petter, Tsingy, Bongolava
    - Lucys Legacy illustrations Author: Stephen Nash, 1950s-90s; letters, photos and cartoons (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Priscilla Barrett, Stephen Nash, Attenborough, Yale, Zambia, Galago
    - Photos and prints, 1960s onwards (Box 5, Folder 4)
      David Chivers, spider monkeys, Jonathan Pollock, Indri prints, Gerald Doyle, Galago, Marcel Hladik, play, Aloatte, howler monkey, Elizabetta Palagi, lagothrix, woolly monkey, Warren Kinzey, squirrel monkey, Desmond Morris, Chimp, Congo, Philp Coffey, Hugo van Lawick, Jean-Jaques Petter, Avani, Gerald Durrell, Bernhard Meier, Heinrich Hofer, Juliette Raznay, Paul Verin, Noeleen Heyzer, World Women's Conference, Maria Patino, Gustav Fischer-Verlag, John Buettner Janusch, Doris
    - Jean de Heaulme portrait, photos (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Jean de Heaulme originals, photos (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - RJ and Alison Jolly photos Author: RJ, Alison Jolly Anzamahavelo, 2000; photos (Box 5, Folder 5)
      funeral at Anzamahavelo "The Lucky Baobarb", Sisal photos, Drurys king
    - Adrian Warren "Sapphire" Author: Adrian Warren Location: Berenty, 1996; photo (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Albino infant Lc, subject of film "A Lemur's Tale"
    - Calao Postcards Author: de Heaulme Fort Dauphin, 1990s; postcards (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Photos from Yale Author: John BJ, Alison Jolly Yale, 1960s; photos (Box 3, Folder 15)
      includes Alison Jolly holding the Kinkajou "Ralph" with Calomella jealous, John BJ, Juvenal, Thurber, Puppet, Sal Hepatica
    - Madagascar stamps Location: Madagascar, envelopes with stamps (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Noel Rowe, Earthwatch Author: Noel Rowe Location: Berenty, 1984; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Rakotoarisoa, one extraordinary photo of 4 colubrid snakes together - mating?
    - Alison Jolly photos Location: Berenty, 1964; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
      EF as part of LC troop
    - L. catta photo named Alison Jolly Location: Portland, Oregon, 1985; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Washington park zoo
    - Alison Jolly in Arashiyama IPS congress, 1992; photo (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - funny pictures of slender loris for Alison Jolly thesis Author: Subramoniam, S. Location:, 1957; illustrations (Box 3, Folder 14)
      from J. Bombay National Hist. Soc.
    - Jean de Heaulm and tortoise Author: Russ Mittermeier Location: Berenty, 1970s; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
      photo Russ Mittermeier
    - Precision Grip Author: John Napier, 1960; photo (Box 3, Folder 14)
      John Napier
    - Lemur Mongoz Comoros Author: Alan Walker, 1970s; photo (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Alan Walker
    - Hanta and friends Location: Berenty, 1984; handwritten letter and photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
      2nd Earthwatch
    - original photo of Tupaia, 1960; magazine photo (Box 3, Folder 14)
      This photo led me to remark to GEH, "If I had my druthers I'd study that - besides it lives a long way from Yale" To which he said, "A fellow in Anthropology has 50 of them." Hence my thesis.
    - drawings of G. crassi-caudatus, Varecia and Aye-aye hand Author: Rogers Location:, 1965; lettter and drawings (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Rogers sent me Galago crassicaudatus, kept in a caged group of trees in Lusaka while MJ was a baby
    - Nash paintings of Megaladapis, Paleopropithecus, Archeolemur Author: Stephen Nash Location:, 1987; prints (Box 3, Folder 14)
      National Geographic
    - Sue Savage-Rumbaugh with Kanzi Bonobo and infant chimps, 1988; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Emory University, Georgia
    - Tupaia Hapalemur photos Author: Alison Jolly Yale, 1962; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - classic primate photos, 1959-60; letter, envelope and photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Harlow loveless rhesus
    - captive pottos Author: AJ Yale, 1962; photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
      captive pottos were sociable and playful, though in slow motion
    - lepilemur photos Location: Yale and Berenty, 1960-70; photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Galago crassicaudatus in caged trees Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lusaka, 1965; photo and negs (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Loris Author: Marcel Hladik Sri Lanka, 1962; photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Loris sampling noxious insect
    - Avahi sonnerat, Aye aye, prints (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - girls with pet ringtailed lemur, photo (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Filanzana watercolour, 1989; watercolour prints (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Malagasy artist
    - A murder in Madagascar Author: David Quammen Location: Madagascar, 1991; magazine article with photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Bedo Jaosolo's murder as conflicting stories. World Bank mission 1989 were the last tourists he took to see indri of Andasibe.
    - Leapin' lemurs, 1983; magazine article with photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
      photo of Andre Peyrieras and aye-aye, National Geog. World
    - Catalogue of lemur skins in the IRSM Author: AJ, Georges Randrianasolo Location: Antananarivo, 1963; handwritten notes (Box 5, Folder 6)
      list of Lemur and Propithecus skins, all now lost, with locations and original attributions, and comments on ones that don't fit. Also first notes for social behavior and intelligence paper.
    - Murder at the Wenner Gren Castle Author: Alison Jolly Location: Burg Wartenstein, Austria, 1969; Typed detective story (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Unfinished detective story set in Wenner Gren Conference on "The animal Nature of Man". Arthur Koestler's "The Call Girls". Summary 2012. Sherwood Washburn, David Ellefson, Judy Ellefson, Robin Fox, Richard Lee, Tom Struhsaker, Lita Osmundsen
    - The Burnt Barley Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1969; Typed stories (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Children's stories for Margaretta: The Burnt Barley, Rufus and the Bears, Eggs for Tea, Rufus and the Romans
    - Primate species distribution and biogeographic provinces Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1970s; Typed paper draft and maps (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Extensive review but I thought not worth publishingb
    - A note on infant adoption by a male Lemur Catta Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1975; Typed paper draft (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Emotional description of infant's death, rejected by journal as too gruesome and unscientific
    - The Rediscovery of Death Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1970s; Typed paper draft (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Infant death, Hrdy infanticide, chimp wars, Dittus' macaques, and on to demography and species' survival or extinction
    - Letter to Gillian Beer. Biologist's reaction to "Darwin's Plots" Author: Alison Jolly Location: From Rome, 1984; Handwritten letter (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Reaction to postmodern Darwin in literature
    - Nationl Geographic conservation proposal Author: Alison Jolly Location: New York, 1985; Typed draft, letters (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Proposal and letters from Alan Boraiko
    - Le Chant de Lemur catta: son rôle dans la défense de territoire et l'éducation des americains.. Author: Alison Jolly Antananarivo, 1985; Typed seminar draft (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Scientific pre-congress to 1985 Environment and Development Conress. Mme Berthe organized. Russ Mittermeier brought his own projector and fused the lights of the Solimotel
    - Reality Check Author: Caroline Moseley Location: Princeton, 1986; Newspaper (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Science wars faculty group, Princeton Weekly Bulletin
    - Structural adjustment and child malnutrition in Mad., Impact of World Recession on the Third World: The Case of Zambia Author: RJ, Catholic Relief Services Location: Antananarivo, Zambia, 1986; Typed letter, paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Rhonda Sarnoff, Catholic Relief Services, Richard Jolly
    - The Environment is where we all live Author: Alison Jolly Location: Delhi, 1987; Typed paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
      For SID meeting Delhi, when Ethel Grant died and we visited Vandana Shiva and Chipko Movement
    - National Geographic, Lemur proposal Author: Alison Jolly Location: New York, 1987; Letters, Budget (Box 3, Folder 17)
      with answers by Alan Boraiko, National Geographic
    - Children, the environment and UNICEF Author: RJ, Alison Jolly Location: New York, 1988; Typed paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
      UNICEF board paper 1988
    - Haraway, Donna: Teddy Bear Postmodernism Lecture Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1990s; Typed notes (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Furious reaction of Robert May and Daniel Rubenstien, Carl Akeley's influence on me
    - Intelligence: the best idea since sex Author: Alison Jolly Location: Santa Cruz, 1990s; Workshop paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
      For Female Biology and Life History workshop, Andrienne Zillman and Mary Ellen Morbeck, conveners
    - A note on female dominance and social structure in the lemurifornes Author: Alison Jolly Location: Bali, 1994; Conference paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
      For IPS Congress, Bali
    - Once there was a millionaire who was interested in anthropology Author: Alison Jolly Location: Teresopolis, Brazil, 1996; Typed notes (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Spoof summary of Wenner-Gren Conference on Gender and Culture in Primatology, Shirley Strum and Linda Fedigan, Conveners
    - Andrew Ate an Ant Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1976; Hand drawn children's book (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Alphabet stories to help RBJ learn to read, told and drawn as he watched, one per day. 2nd grade
    - Ann adopted an Adder sample illustrations, Andrew ate an ant Author: AJ, Victoria Cowan Lewes, 1979; incomplete book, pen and ink on card (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Girl's version of Andrew, Vicky Cowan, Yew Tree Cottage, Southover High Street
    - Rejection letters Author: various London, 1978-9; Typed letters (Box 3, Folder 20)
      From MacMillan, Hamish Hamilton, John Vernon Lord Artist, Jonathan Cape, Penguin, Eyre Methuen, and Philippa Stoker free-lance
    - Murder on the Bird Tour Author: Alison Jolly Mauritius, 1980; Typed detective story (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Reaction to being a tour guide. I killed the most objectionable in the first paragraph, and on from there.
    - Bonobo Field notebook Author: Alison Jolly Wamba, Zaire, 1994; small notebook (Box 3, Folder 20)
      BBC visit for "Monkey in the Mirror"
    - Bonobo Anthropologist Author: Alison Jolly Wamba, Zaire, 1994; address (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Dr. Daiji KIMURA, Wamba anthroplogist
    - Talking drum letter Author: Lingomo-Bongoli Location: Wamba, Zaire, 1994; handwritten letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Why talking drums use metaphorical and poetic language,and parallels with Bonobo communication from Zairois head of Kyoto Bonobo study
    - Talking drums, squeaking chimpanzees and quarks of speech Author: Alison Jolly Location: Wamba, Zaire, 1994; Typed draft (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Draft academic article on talking drums and origins of language
    - Talking drum letter, Lysa Author: Lysa- Location: Princeton, 1994; Typed letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Letter re talking drums
    - Talking drum letter, Steven Pinker Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1994; Typed letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Letter to Steven Pinker re talking drums
    - Talking drum letter Sue Savage-Rumbaugh Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1994; Typed letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Letter to Sue Savage Rumbaugh re talking drums
    - Yoruba talking drums article Author: Ajayi, Bade Location: Nigeria, 1994; Article (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Use of drums in social motivations
    - Talking drums letter Author: Sue Savage Rumbaugh Location: Georgia State Univ., 1994; Typed letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Letter re Wamba bonobos
    - Protecting bonobos by inalimental conditions: the case of the Bongando Author: Lingomo-Bongoli Wamba, Zaire, 1994; Typed draft (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Article on bonobo conservation by Zairois head of Japanese bonobo project
    - The Kiloopy-Loopy-Soofy and the Very Old Man Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1995; Typed story (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Childdren's story of living fossils after talking with David Burney
    - Behaviour in the Bottleneck Author: Ajayi, Bade Location: Madison, Wisconsin, 1996; Typed draft (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Primatology changing from the study of evolution to future conservation ecology
    - Mark's Maky Author: AJ, 2009; Typed story (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Detective story Author: AJ Madagascar, 1980; Typed story (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Historic Maps of Madagascar Location: Madagascar, maps (Box 5, Folder 7)
      1954 1:500,000 10 part series, post independence: 1: 500,00 12 part series, Inst. Nat. de Geodesie et Cartographie, formations vegetales de Mad. 1: 100,000. PNUD, CI, ANGAP, E andF 1990s, Humbert, H and Cours - Darne 1964 Carte Internationle du Tapis Vegetal, Madagascr 1: 100,000 with inset maps of geology, soils etc. Inst. francais de Pondicherry based on air photos 1950. 1964 1: 500,000 12 part, Inst. Geographique de Paris, 1973 1:50,000, sheets for Ranomafana-Ifanadiana and Kianjavato.
    - Historic Maps of Madagascar Location: Madagascar, maps (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
    - Document pour le seminaire Location: Madagascar, 2006; document and newspaper (Box 4, Folder 1)
      etude sur l'approvisionnement en eau potable autonome et durable dans la region du sud de la republique de madagascar
    - Report of CARE's 2003 joint baseline surveys Author: Megan Deitchler and Gilles Bergeron Antanarivo and Fort Dauphin, Madagascar, 2004; document (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Madagascar food insecurity Location: Madagascar, 2003; map (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Madagascar aids law Location: Madagascar, 2005; document (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - USAID SAVEM meetings Location: Madagascar, 1997; notes and document (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - USAID PE2 meetings Location: Madagascar, 1997; document (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - small notebook Author: AJ Madagascar, 2002; handwritten notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Des racines pour des ailes Author: Roland Ramahatra Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - projet radio Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Andrew lees trust, Early warning system using radio broadcast for southern Madagascar
    - Victor Ramahatra Author: Nivo Ramahatra Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed letter (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Conservation of critical biodiversity habitats 1990 to present Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
      USAID
    - Sustainable use of forest resources 1990 to present Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Involvement of private sector in better managing natural resources Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Twelve years later Location: Madagascar and Washington, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Twelve years later evolution of USAID/Madagascar's environment program
    - revue strategique du programme de l'usaid Location: Madagascar, 2001; document (Box 4, Folder 5)
      USAID, revue strategique du programme de l'usaid dans le domaine de l'environment a madagascar
    - letters from Harvard Press and Houghton Mifflin on Lords and Lemurs Location: Princeton and Berenty, 2001-2; typed letters (Box 4, Folder 10)
      scathing criticism and my rebuttal on Lords and Lemurs, "The Narrator's Stance", Kauffmann
    - Lords and Lemurs statements Location: Berenty, 2000; typed notes (Box 4, Folder 10)
      statements by Jean de Heaulme of family, business and sisal
    - official documents Berenty estate Location: Berenty, 1930s-50s; documents (Box 4, Folder 10)
      The founding of Berenty as a French "concession"
    - original notebooks Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1998-2000; handritten notebooks (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - notes and interviews for Lords and Lemurs Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 2000s?; notes, notebooks, typed and handwritten (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Rehomanas notebook of first sisal workers, Andreas Mina, guide, Rakotalahy, Maavopaly, Fagnanea guardian, Filomana forest guard, Genevieve maid, Honnette and Georgette trieuses, Rehomaha, Seconde, Rekanoky, Sambiany schoolteacher, Pierre-Robson, Mbol, Tahina Nirina, Jean de Heaulme, list of 5 frenchmen imprisoned in Ft. Dauphin, name of sculptor of Berenty Alo Alos: VALESOA of Andriambaly village near Beloha
    - The Narrator's Stance: storytelling and Science at Berenty Reserve Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 2010; Typed article (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Permissions, 2000s; typed letters (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Franz Lanting, R. Mittermeier, Tom Lovejoy, Sheila O'Connor, Sarah Hrdy, Colin Radford, Nick Garbutt,
    - Robert Drury Location: Princeton, 2003; manuscripts and letters (Box 4, Folder 13)
      attempts to sell as screenplay to LRB and National Geographic
    - letter to RJ Author: AJ Ambaro and Berenty, 1996; handwritten letter (Box 4, Folder 13)
      original full account of visit to Ambaro, the village of the king who captured Robert Drury, Georges Heurtebize, George Macdonald, Joanne Macdonald
    - interview with Pierre Ramahatra Author: Alison Jolly Location: Antananarivo, 2000; handwritten interview transcription (Box 4, Folder 13)
      The events of 1947, Fort Dauphin
    - Rencontre avec L'Androy Author: Georges Heurtebize Location:, typed account (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Georges Heurtebize and how he fell in love with Androy, Tandroy anthropology
    - notes on travel with Georges Heurtebize, George and Joanna Macdonald Author: Alison Jolly Location: Ambaro, 1996; typed notes (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Dunes at mouth of Mandrare, the Drury mssacre site, Sarah Fee's weaver village Ambaro, the king's village.
    - Rites Funeraires Tandroy, Kokolampo: Possession Author: Philibert Tsimamandro University of Tulear, 1998; typed summary of thesis (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - independence of Madagascar, 1946 Author: Jacques and Raymond Rabemananjara Location: Neuilly, France, 1946; typed document (Box 4, Folder 13)
      debates before the Assemble Nationale Constuante on the possible independence of Madagascar 1946
    - interviews with Jean de Heaulme Author: Alison Jolly Location: Fort Dauphin, 1998-2000; handwritten and typed notes (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Rehomahas notebook of names Location: Berenty, 1930s; typed list (Box 4, Folder 14)
      all original Berenty workers by village, dedicated to his wife Seconde who had been to the plantation school and could read
    - interview notes Author: AJ Berenty, 1998-2000; typed notes (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Andreas Miha, Rakotolahy, Fagnanea, Ndaisoa, Filomana, Genevievy, Prospere Sambiavy, Rekanoky, Rehomana, Tsiminono, Tsiaketraky
    - tourist interviews Author: Alison Jolly, 2000; typed notes (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - July-Oct Diary Author: AJ Lewes and Sark, 1999; diary notebook (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Berenty interviews
    - interview Chantal and Georges du Pray Author: Alison Jolly Location: Sainte foy la grande, 1999; typed and handwritten notes, photo and guide (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - interview Guy and Eliane Marcou Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lamonzie St. Martin France, 2000; handwritten letters and photos (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - interview Maitre Christophie Author: Alison Jolly Fort Dauphin, 2003; notebook and letters (Box 4, Folder 14)
      1947 people condemned to death in Fort D.
    - letters between Duke students, 1970s; handwritten letters (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Kathryn Dainis Blumenfeld-jones, Norman Budritz, Lee McGeorge Durrell, Jay Russell, Anne Mertl Millhollen
    - Madagascar Matin, 1972; photocopied news article (Box 4, Folder 14)
      first edition, after arson of printers stopped the courrier de Mad. With politicians photos including Ratsimandrava and Ratsiraka
    - Aina R'Abel Author: AJ Berenty, 1990s; handwritten notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Hanta's niece who came as teenage Earthwatch volunteer, first impressions of Berenty by a girl from Tana
    - Madagascar Mica mining, photocopied news article (Box 4, Folder 5)
      The de Heaulmes were originally mica miners.
    - La Carte Imperiale Author: Maurice Martin du Gard, 1940-45; photocopied chapter (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Editions Andre Bonne, Paris, Madagascar chapter. The best account of Mad. in colonial and Vichy WWII
    - Brochure of Arambelo Author: Georges Heurtebize Location: Berenty, brochure (Box 4, Folder 5)
      The Berenty Museum of Tandroy life, paid by J de H, designed by Georges Heurtebize and Sarah Fee
    - de Heaulme photo Author: Sheila O'Connor Berenty, 1985; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Joseph Randrianasolo, Ministre des E and F, Russ Mittermeier, Duke of Edinburgh, Jean de Heaulme, Mark Pidgeon
    - de Heaulme photo, 1990s; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
      Jean de Heaulme, Claire de Heaulme, Aline de Heaulme, Benedict de Heaulme
    - La Basse Terre Location: Reunion, C19th?; photograph (Box 5, Folder 8)
      de Heaulme's home, Reunion